As is the case with any network-based objects,
databases should be subject to the principle of
least privilege (PoLP), which is a principle that
states that people should have, from a permissions
standpoint, what they need to do their jobs, but
no more than that. For databases, this is true
both on a database level and an object level
within a database, such as the table level.
To get an idea of how permissions work in a
database such as this one, I will select and hold
(or right-click) the AdventureWorks database,
select Properties, and then Permissions. Of
interest is this public role. I will select
it, and we see that this public role has
very few permissions on the database, which
is the way it should be as anyone who sees
this database is in the public role. Let's
see what permissions look like on objects.
I will select and hold (or
right-click) the Person.Address table,
select Properties, and then select Permissions.
No one has explicit permissions on this table,
and again, that is by design, as permissions
should be controlled first on a database level
and then on an object level. If we want to grant
a permission to a user or group, we can search
for that group. I have added a dbanalyst
group to this database, and I will search
for that group. From here, I can grant or deny
specific permissions on this table to this group.
I will grant Select permissions to this
role, which will allow anyone in this
role to run SELECT queries, queries that gather
information from this table. With this principle,
it is a good idea to start a database
with minimal or no permissions granted
and then grant those permissions as needed. Again,
people should have just the permissions they need.